准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
空手道闺蜜
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啊  闺蜜帮
Ah, zee Gal Pals
裤头村顶级的女子联盟
Bikini Bottom's premier ladies league
今天  可以看到她们在互相分享绝活
Today, we find them
sharing their special skills with one another
给我一个闺
Gimme a G
给我一个蜜
Gimme an A
给我一个帮
Gimme an L
总共有三个字
Gimme a P-A-L-S
合起来是什么
What does it spell?
闺蜜帮
Gal Pals
那个啦啦队技巧
That cheerleading technique
可能对我们还是太高深了点  珍珍
may be a little too advanced for us, Pearl
然后上传鸡蛋  瞧好了
Then, upload the eggs, and voila
我的招牌全息肉糕
My famous holographic meatloaf
怎么样
Well?
好不好吃啊
What do you think?
非常好吃
That was delicious
而且
and, uh
没什么饱腹感
not too filling
口味还挺清淡的
It certainly has a light flavor
早知道就带零食来了
We should've brought snacks
你打算跟大家分享什么呢  泡芙老师
And what are you sharing with us, Mrs. Puff?
下面是发动汽船的一个小妙招
Here's an easy way to start your boat
以防你碰巧
Just in case you happen to
丢了钥匙
lose your keys
这下知道
Now I know
钥匙被老爸藏起来  还能怎么开船了
what to do when Daddy hides the boat keys
如果你们觉得那叫酷的话
If'n y'all thought that was cool
等着瞧我秀几招空手道吧
wait till you see my karate demonstration
松鼠功
Squirrel style
我的伺服电机可不是造来打架的
My servos are not built for combat
我是老师  不是打手
I'm a teacher, not a fighter
我太娇嫩  动不了武
I'm too delicate for martial arts
是吗
Oh yeah?
这一招可能会让你们改变主意哦
This here move might change your mind
停得真漂亮
Nice parking job
了不起
Impressive
我太想学空手道了
I totally wanna learn karate
学着我做
Now do as I do
而且别忘了全力以赴
and remember, give it all your gumption
松鼠功
Squirrel style
几小时后
这空手道课上得可真是带劲
That was one humdinger of a karate lesson
我等不及要上下一节课了
I can't wait until our next one
恐怕已经没什么可教的了
'Fraid there ain't much more I can teach you
说实话  你们学得太棒了
In fact, y'all are such great students
所以我要给你们颁发终极橡子腰带
I'm awardin' you my ultimate acorn belt
毛茸茸的
So fuzzy
谢谢
Thank you
我  我可能需要个小点的尺寸
I-I may need a smaller size
松鼠功
Squirrel Style
下周见  闺蜜帮
See you next week, Gal Pals
闺蜜帮
老爸
Daddy
我回来了
I'm home
我在楼上  乖女儿珍珍
I'm up here, Pearly girl
你可算是来了
Well, it's about time
你没洗的臭衣服都堆成山了
Your stinky laundry's piling up
老爸啊
Oh, Daddy
才没有那么臭呢
It's not that bad
真没那么臭吗
Not that bad, eh?
好好好
Fine
臭烘烘的破衣服
Stupid stinky clothes
松鼠功
Squirrel style
这一劈  很清新
Karate fresh
还有什么是空手道做不到的呢
Is there anything karate can't do?
快啊  你这破铜烂铁
Come on, you pile of flotsam
我下节上课就要迟到了
I'll be late for my next lesson
比接线点火还简单
Even easier than hot-wiring it
海之霸
老婆好
Hi, hon
只是在把我的变异
Just putting my mutant
海霸糊怪
chum monster
捉回笼子里
back in its cage
好  大力士
Sure, Hercules
我来帮你吧
Let me give you a hand
不错嘛
Not ba--
松鼠功
Squirrel style
我是珊迪  有求必应
Y'all reached Sandy, the squirrel that's handy
珊迪  我是痞老板
Sandy, it's Plankton
快来帮帮我
You have to help me
出了什么麻烦呢
What seems to be the trouble?
凯伦失控了
Karen's outta control
不管你之前对她干嘛了  赶紧撤销掉
Undo whatever you did to her
干嘛怪我
Well, what are you blamin' me for?
松鼠功
Squirrel style
懂了
Point taken
你好啊  凯伦
How-do, Karen?
在干嘛呢
What you up to?
抱歉  珊迪
Sorry, Sandy
我现在忙着重新装修实验室
but I'm a little busy redecorating the lab
拆毁还差不多
More like demolishing
这下门口有风水了
Now the doorway is feng shui
你这空手道打得可能有点过头了
You may have gone a little overboard on the karate
这明明就是你说的那个
It's like you said
全力以赴
Give it all your gumption
松鼠功
Squirrel style
我好像还真那么说了
I did say that, didn't I?
这地方一直缺个窗户
This place always needed a window
松鼠功
Squirrel style
不好了
Oh no
我等会儿回来
Be back later
什么
What?
欢迎随时过来
Drop by anytime
快逃命啊
Run for your life
保命要紧
Save yourselves
毁大号简直惨无人道啊
The tuba-manity
一个空一个手一个道
Gimme a K-A-R-A-T-E
合起来是什么
What's it spell?
空手道
Karate
嗨  珊迪
Hi, Sandy
珍珍  我感觉啦啦队跟空手道
Pearl, I'm not sure cheerleading and karate
好像不太搭
are a great mix
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
多亏了空手道
Thanks to karate
我现在是全校最棒的啦啦队员了
I am the best cheerleader in school
没错
It's true
她可神了
She's amazing
可我还是觉得不太
But I still don't think--
松鼠功
Squirrel style
不好了
Oh no
还是请你少打点空手道好吗  珍珍
Try to tone down the karate, will ya, Pearl?
松鼠功
Squirrel style
好
松鼠功
Squirrel style
泡芙到底在搞什么鬼
What in tarnation is Puff doin'?
你好
Howdy
在干嘛呢
Whatcha doin'?
嗨  珊迪
Hi, Sandy
我把你那个厉害的空手道技巧
I've integrated your wonderful karate skills
融入到我的驾驶课里了
into my driver's training
终于能好好给海绵宝宝上课了
I can finally give SpongeBob lessons
不会再伤害到别人了
without anyone getting hurt
别忘了打转向灯  海绵宝宝
Don't forget your turn signal, SpongeBob
你那个新的教学方式
Your new teaching method is
别开上人行道
Get off the sidewalk
太有效率了  泡芙老师
certainly effective, Mrs. Puff
我觉得你终于准备好了  海绵宝宝
I think you're finally ready, SpongeBob
踩油门
Floor it
踩油门吗
Floor it?
听到了吧
You heard me
油门踩到底
Pedal to the metal
松鼠功
Squirrel Style
不好了
Oh no
我创造了三个空手道怪物
I've created three karate monsters
松鼠功
Squirrel style
嗨  珊迪
Hi, Sandy
虽然今晚得练空手道
I know we're supposed to practice karate tonight
可这驾驶课上得简直累死我了
but my driving lesson really took a lot out of me
天啊  海绵宝宝
Gosh, SpongeBob
真对不起
I'm sorry
自从我给闺蜜帮上了空手道课
Ever since I gave the Gal Pals karate lessons
她们个个都成了跆拳呆
they've all gone tae kwon dodo
如果说问题是教会她们空手道引起的
Well, if teaching them karate caused the problem
那就反过来  把教的都收回来
why don't you just un-teach it?
那简直是最傻的一个建议
Well, that would be the dumbest suggestion ever
好在我早就发明了个反向空手道矩阵
if'n I hadn't already invented a reverse karate matrix
完全可以实现你的建议
that does exactly that
第一步  瞄准泡芙
Step one: Zero in on Puff
珍珍  和凯伦的大脑
Pearl, and Karen's brains
我能帮忙吗
Can I help?
当然可以了
Why, sure
你就只要转动那个旋钮
All you gotta do is twist that dial
拉动这根拉杆  往上扳那开关
pull this here lever, flip those switches
压那踏板  再按下这小按钮
press that pedal, and push this little button
做一百次
Do that a hundred times
按刚刚的顺序来
In that order
我
I'm
准备好了吗
ready?
现在我只要反向使出空手道招数就行
Now all I have to do
is perform all my karate moves in reverse
按那颗按钮  压那个踏板
Push that button, press that pedal
按那根拉杆
push that lever
转那个旋钮吗
Twist that dial?
第二天早上
这样应该就行了
That oughta do it
万岁
Whoopee
闺蜜帮的空手道危害不到裤头村了
Bikini Bottom is safe from the Gal Pals' karate chaos
松鼠功
Squirrel style
并非如此
Maybe not
我要把脚邮寄到你面前  布兰奇
I'm gonna deliver my foot to your face, Blanche
你好大的胆子
How dare you
这空手道很适合用来健身
This karate stuff is a great workout
你打不过我的末日转轮
You are no match for my spinning wheels of doom
看我大力使出
Behold the power of
我的腿
my leg
你当时扳开关跟按按钮的顺序没错吧
You did make sure to flip all the switches
and push the buttons in the correct order, right?
好像我该往上扳的时候往下扳了
I may have flicked when I should've flipped
真见鬼
Dang-gummit
没让闺蜜帮忘掉空手道
Instead of de-karateing the Gal Pals
反倒让裤头村所有人成了空手道大师
I done turned everyone in town into a karate master
空手道太神了
Ka-ra-te is ah-mazing
助步器旋风劈
Spinning walker whirlwind
现在该怎么办
Now what do we do?
不知道  不过大伙儿玩得还挺开心
No idea, but they're sure having fun
既然大家都摸透了彼此之间的招数
I guess since everyone knows each other's karate moves
那就没人能分得出输赢
no one is winning or losing
既然没人受伤
And if no one's getting hurt
那就没有问题了
There's no problem
那么打不过就加入吧
Well, if'n you can't beat 'em, join 'em
好不好啊
Shall we?
你先请  师傅
After you, sensei
松鼠功
Squirrel style
于是  多亏了闺蜜帮
And so, thanks to zee Gal Pals
我们得向裤头村珍重告别
we must bid adieu to Bikini Bottom
打招呼迎接  空手道村
and say bonjour to Karate Bottom
空手道村
凯伦的茶话会
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海之霸
上好餐巾被我放哪了
Where did I put the good napkins?
好多了
That's better
这样是不是很好看啊  痞老板
Doesn't this look nice, Plankton?
痞老板
Plankton?
凯伦
Karen
帮我续杯
Need a refill
顺便再帮我打点薯片
And some more chips while you're at it
痞老板
Plankton
都跟你说了
I told you
我有几位电脑朋友今天要来共进午餐
my computer friends are coming over today for lunch
马上给我把这堆破烂搬你实验室去
You need to move all of this into your lab right now
还共进午餐啊
That's still happening?
可惜我还要追剧呢
Too bad, I'm watching my stories
要追剧就在这里面追
You can watch your "stories" in here
其实  你最好一直待在里面
In fact, it might be best if you stayed in here
等我朋友走了再出来
until my friends leave
什么
What?
不准把我晾在一边
You can't put me on ice
是嫌我丢人吗
Are you ashamed of me?
当然不是了
Of course not
他们来了
They're here
给我待在里面
Stay in here for me
应该能拦住他了
That oughta hold him
电脑茶话会的小伙伴们好
Hey, computer klatch
欢迎光临海之霸
Welcome to the Chum Bucket
你好
Hello
你好哦
Greetings
怎么
What the?
一群鬼东西哔哔个不停
Bunch of babbling beepers
反正我还得干活呢
I've got work to do anyway
好久不见了  凯伦
It's been way too long, Karen
我也很高兴再见到你  坦迪
Great to see you too, Tandy
自从我们上次寒暄几句以来
Since we last exchanged pleasantries
我编码了7486099个二进制文件
I have encoded 7,486,099 new files of binary code
00011111111000000000
00011111111000000000--
音量调低一点  兄弟
Dial it down, dude
你近来如何  比姆
And how are things with you, BIM?
要不要来抱一个
"How about a hug?"
过来吧
Come here
别这么用力
"Not so hard"?
抱歉  比姆
Sorry, BIM
开个玩笑嘛
"Just kidding
我又没有知觉什么的
I have no feelings of sensation whatsoever"
啥玩意突然就那么好笑了
What's so funny all of a sudden?
看看他们
Look at 'em
多半在议论我
I bet they're talking about me
还在嘲笑我
They're laughing at me
一定要知道他们在哔哔我什么东西
I gotta know what they're beeping and bleeping about me
有办法了
I know what to do
不好意思
Excuse me
我应该得去上个洗手间
I guess I have to use the little calculator's room
比姆  当时是你说了
BIM, you were the one who said--
早知道出门之前就上了
I should have done this before I left the house
执行下载程序
Commence download
终于啊
Finally
坦迪回来了
Tandy's back
咋了
What?
是掉马桶里了吗
Did you fall in?
确实  猜猜我还撞见谁了
Yes I did fall in, and guess who I ran into?
母
你们的主板
Your motherboard
太过分了吗
Too much?
你啊
You
真好笑  坦迪
Good one, Tandy
她信了
She bought it
那么
So, uh
我错过了什么有料的坏话没
what juicy trash talk did I miss?
有料的坏话
Juicy trash talk?
是指恶意软件故障吗
You mean a "malware glitch"?
不对
No
文件损坏吗
"Corrupt files"?
不对
No
才不是黑客
Not "Hackers"
我指的是八卦
I mean gossip
家丑  传闻
Dirty laundry, rumors
谣言  闲话
canards, tittle-tattles
快快爆料
Spill the tea
谁的八卦
About who?
不知道  比如说
I don't know, like, uh
凯伦的丈夫
Karen's husband?
就是说  那个绿色的小怪东西咋回事
I mean, what is the deal with that little green weirdo?
我说得对吧
Am I right?
配餐的来了
The caterer is here
还有配餐啊
Catering?
好高级
Fancy
原来他们并没有议论我
I guess they're not talking about me after all
凭什么不议论我
Why aren't they talking about me?
电脑茶话会
Computer klatch
我是你们的服务生  海绵机
I am your server, SpongeBot
邀请你们来大吃特吃这一GB
And I invite you to take a giga-bite
蟹堡王的美食
of the Krusty Krab's delectable comestibles
蟹堡王吗
The Krusty Krab?
有蜂蜜辣芥末螺帽螺栓
We've got spicy honey-mustard nuts and bolts
奶酪软盘
cheesy floppy discs
以及电脑芯片  配散热硅脂
and computer chips with thermal grease
好吃好吃
Yum, yum, yum
电脑食物吗
Computer food?
垃圾
Lame
我还要用勺子给大家
And I will spoon feed you all
都来喂一口这道辣菜
a sample of this spicy concoction
这口给你
And one for you
我自己就能吃这
I can feed my--
可以失陪一下吗
Would you excuse me for a moment?
不知道坦迪为什么老是往洗手间跑
I wonder why Tandy keeps going to the restroom
应该检查一下他
I should check on him
不好了
Oh no
得检查他的生命体征  看有没有病毒
I'll check his vital signs for a virus
看来这病毒
Looks like this "virus"
不愿意老实听话  乖乖待在实验室里
couldn't just stay in his lab like I asked
你没事吧  坦迪
Everything okay in here, Tandy?
一点赛博网络病罢了
Just a little cyber-sickness
总之这次拜访很美好
Anyway, I've had a lovely visit
但我觉得自己应该要回家断电了
but I think I should go home and power down
可别这就开溜啊  坦迪
You can't bail on us now, Tandy
派对才刚要开始呢
The party is just getting started
来玩个电脑室内游戏吧
Let's play a computer parlor game
有了  来玩电火花手指吧
I know, let's play Sparky Finger
要不来玩一玩电脑叠罗汉
Or how about Compu-Tower
到你了  坦迪
Your turn, Tandy
好主意  比姆
Great idea, BIM
谁想玩
Who wants to play
拳打粉碎机器人大战
"Punch 'Em Crunch 'Em Robots"
拳打吗
Punch 'em?
粉碎吗
Crunch 'em?
大家装好数字拳头  准备好打得
Put up your digital dukes and get ready to have your
脑袋开花吧
Noggin knocked off
笨死了
The stupidity
戴上手套  坦迪
Put your gloves on, Tandy
现在这个时候应该适合我来
This would probably be a good time for me to, uh
出口
什么
What?
第一回合
Round one
第二回合
Round two
这电脑茶话会好疯狂啊
These computer klatch parties are insane
第三回合
Round three
又来了
Not again
来个左勾拳
Give 'em a left
右勾拳
And a right
再一记正中下巴的上勾拳
And a line drive right up the middle
干嘛不玩算数字账的游戏
Why don't we play a game that crunches numbers
别打我脑袋  算我的账
instead of heads?
我知道你就在里面  痞老板
I know you're in there, Plankton
而且我要把你打得脑袋开花
and I'm knockin' your noggin off
那不是坦迪
That's not Tandy
谢尔顿  你干什么偷窥我们
Alright, Sheldon, why were you spying on us?
我以为你跟你朋友都嫌弃我  抹黑我
Well, I thought you and your friends were hating on me
你这小不点是在被害妄想吧
You paranoid pipsqueak
我们才不讨厌你
We don't hate you
所以说你们没对我生气吗
You-you mean you're not mad at me?
没有哦
No
不过有个人肯定很生气
But I know someone who is
把我身体还回来
Give me back my body
等等
Wait
别
No
对不起
I'm sorry
哔
Beep